Guide to the Council of School Supervisors and Administrators Records WAG.269
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II: General Files, 1945-2007
  - New York State Federation of School Administrators, 1992-2007 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - New York State: Legislative Correspondence, 1972-1977 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - New York State Public Employee Relations Board (PERB), 1974-1977 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - New York Supervisor (NYCESPA publication), 1979-1986 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - New York Urban Coalition: Principals Network, 1978-1982 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - O'Brien, Peter S. (President): Biographical and General, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - O'Brien, Peter S.: Column, 1974-1977 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - O'Brien, Peter S.: The Other Union (essay on CSA history), 1977 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Officers, Staff, and Committees: Lists, 1967-1970 (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Officers, Staff, and Committees: Lists, 1971-1983 (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Officers, Staff, and Committees: Lists, 1986-2003 (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Open School Week, 1981-1982 (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Organizing Committee for Curriculum Council, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - Parent Associations and the Schools (brochure), 1973-1979 (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Personnel Division, 1981-1982 (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - Political Action Committee (COPE) and Endorsements, 1980-2003 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Press Releases, 1969-1975 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Principal Application (Blank), 1973 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Principal Internship Program, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Principal Performance Review: Press Briefing, 1998 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Principals Lists: Clippings, 1980-1985 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Professional Development Institute: Interviews, 1966; 1984-1985 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Public Relations, 1968; 1973 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Public School 65K, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Public Schools of New York City Staff Bulletin, 1970-1972 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Publicity, 1990-2003; 2007 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Quotas: Response to HEW Secretary Califano, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Residency Requirement, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Retroactive Salary Adjustment, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Riesel, Victor: Moscow Red Faced and Money from Mao?, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Role of Auxiliary Teacher Committee, 1968 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - School Administrators and Supervisors Organizing Committee, 1972-1976 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - School Safety Committee Members, 1975-1976 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Seniority and Staff Layoffs, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Sex Discrimination: Rubin Maloff Case, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Singer, Donald (President), 1989-2000 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Social Security Administration, 1970; 1973 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Special Education: Exam Preparation, 1981 (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Staff, 2001-2003 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Staff and Floor Plan, 1995 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Staff: Meetings, etc., 1973; 1977 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Steering Committee, 1968 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Steering Committee, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - Steering Committee, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - Steering Committee, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - Steering Committee, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - Steering Committee, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 32)
  - Steering Committee, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 33)
  - Student Rights, 1963-1971 (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - Students' School Almanac (samples in English and Spanish), 1992 (Box 20, Folder 35)
  - Summer 1968 Fact Sheets (Box 20, Folder 36)
  - Super Center Consortium, Undated (Box 20, Folder 37)
  - Superintendent of Schools City of New York: Annual Reports, 1953-1956 (Box 20, Folder 38)
  - Supervisors Workshop in School-Community Relations, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 39)
  - Supervisory Rating Plan, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 40)
  - Supervisory/Teaching Titles: Procedures for Approval, 1972-1973 (Box 20, Folder 41)
  - Teacher Education Conference Board Newsletter, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 42)
  - Teacher Organizing: United Teachers-CIO, Teachers Guild, 1950-1956 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Teachers Strike (I), 1975 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Teachers Strike (II), 1975 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Teachers Strike: Clippings (I), 1950 (Box 21, Folder 3a)
  - Teachers Strike: Clippings (II), 1975 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Teachers Strike: Clippings (III), 1975 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Teachers Strike: CSA Position, 1975 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Tenure, 1971-1990 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Toward Excellence in Urban Public Schools, 1988 (Box 21, Folder 7a)
  - Union of School Supervisors, 1963-1968 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Unionization: A Complement to Professionalism, W. Degnan, Undated (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - United Federation of Teachers (UFT), 1973-1995 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - United Federation of Teachers and CSA: Minutes of Meeting with Dr. Gross, 1964 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - United Federation of Teachers: Civil Rights Conference, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - United Parents Association of New York City: Brochure and Conferences, 1952-1956; 1976-1978 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - United Parents Association of New York City: Conferences, 1981 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Urban Parents Association, 1969-1970 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Wagner and La Guardia Archives, La Guardia Community College, 1994 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Website (Captured Images), 2002; 2004 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Welfare Fund, 1965-1970 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Welfare Fund, 1971-1972 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Welfare Fund, 1973-1974 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Welfare Fund, 1975-1976 (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Welfare Fund, 1977-1978 (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Welfare Fund, 1979-1980 (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Welfare Fund, 1981-1984 (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Welfare Fund, 1985-2001 (Box 21, Folder 25)
- Series III: Jacob (Jack) Zuckerman Files, 1962-2007
  Series III: Jacob (Jack) Zuckerman Files, 1962-2007, is comprised of material from the personal files of Jack Zuckerman, long-time CSA activist, who served first as executive vice-president of the union and (from 1974) as president. The series includes his correspondence (both on CSA business and other matters) and his desk diaries. After his retirement Zuckerman, who contributed columns on CSA history to the union's publication, CSA News, acted as the historian of the union, compiled its records for transfer the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, and served as the CSA's representative to the New York Labor History Association. His files reflect his wide-ranging interests in labor history and labor-related social and legislative issues.
  - Clippings, 1959-1967 (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - Clippings, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - Clippings, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - Clippings, 1970 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1971 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1973 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Clippings, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Clippings, 1978-1979 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Clippings, 1980-1983 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Clippings, 1985-1989 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Clippings, 1990-1994 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Clippings, 1995 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Clippings, 1996-1997 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Clippings, 1998 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Clippings, 1999 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Clippings, 2000-2002 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Clippings, 2003-2004 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Clippings, 2005-2007 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Clippings on Parents and Children, 1967-1968 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Clippings and Memorabilia (Personal), 1952-1990 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1972 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 1973 (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 22, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1995-1997 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 2001-2003 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 2004-2006 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Debra Bernhardt (NYU, Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives), 2001 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Desk Diaries, 1968-1972 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Desk Diaries, 1974-1975 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Desk Diaries, 1976-1977 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Desk Diaries, 1978-1979 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Desk Diaries, 1980-1981 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Desk Diaries, 1982-1983 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Elections, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - History of CSA and Archives, 1960-2008 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Handwritten Notes (for Columns), 1976-1994 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Jewish Labor Committee, 1969; 1990s (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Jewish Labor Committee, 2000-2007 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Labor History, General, 1955-1987; 2003 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Labor History Organizations, 1993-2005 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Local 1199's Bread and Roses Conference on Workers Culture, 1993 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - New York Labor History Association (I), 1988-2006 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - New York Labor History Association (II), 1988-2006 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - New York Labor History Association (III), 1988-2006 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - New York Labor History Association (IV), 1988-2006 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - New York State Archives, 1999-2004 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Personal Profile, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Principals Examination, 1963-1966 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Principals List and Officers, 1967-1971 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Queens College, 1996-2000 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Records Management and Preservation, 1993 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Speech (notes), 1977 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - "Twenty-five Years Ago" (clippings), 1989-2000 (Box 24, Folder 16)
- Series IV: Council of School Supervisors and Administrators Retirees Chapter Files, 1972-2007
  Series IV: Council of Supervisors and Administrators Retirees Chapter Files, 1972-2007, documents the history of the Retired School Supervisors and Administrators (RSSA; originally Retired Supervisors Group) and its evolution from an independent organization to an affiliate of the Council of Supervisors and Administrators. Included are materials on RSSA constitutions and by-laws, conferences, legislative activity, local chapters, and social activities, as well as Executive Board minutes, correspondence, membership records, and merger with the CSA retirees' chapter in 2005.
  - Retired School Supervisors and Administrators (RSSA): American Federation of School Administrators- Chapter Applications, 1995-2003 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Retired School Supervisors and Administrators (RSSA): Auditor's Report, 1999 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Retired School Supervisors and Administrators (RSSA): Benefits, 1992; 2006 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Retired School Supervisors and Administrators (RSSA): Benefits Brochures, 1986-2005 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Retired School Supervisors and Administrators (RSSA): Calendar of Activities, 1996 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - RSSA: Chapters-List, 2007 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - RSSA: Chapters-Long Island, 1998-2006 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - RSSA: Chapters-Palm Beach, 1991-2001 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - RSSA: Chapters-South Florida, 1995-2000 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - RSSA: Chapters-South Florida, 2001-2005 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - RSSA: Chapters-South Florida (Directories), 1991-1996 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - RSSA: Chapters-Staten Island, 2001-2002 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - RSSA: Charter Schools, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - RSSA: Chast, Roz, 2004 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - RSSA: Clippings, 1989-2007 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - RSSA: Coalition of Unions Representing NYC Board of Education Employees, 1995 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - RSSA: Conference (Annual), 2005 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - RSSA: Constitution and By-Laws, 1991 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - RSSA: Constitution and By-Laws, 1989-1997 (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - RSSA: Constitution and By-Laws, 1998 (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - RSSA: Constitution and By-Laws, 2000 (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - RSSA: Constitution and By-Laws, 2002 (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - RSSA: Constitution and By-Laws, 2004 (Box 25, Folder 23)
  - RSSA: Constitution and By-Laws, 2005 (Box 25, Folder 24)
  - RSSA: Constitution and By-Laws, 2006 (Box 25, Folder 25)
  - RSSA: Constitution and By-Laws, 2008 (Box 25, Folder 26)
  - RSSA: Correspondence, 1996 (Box 25, Folder 27)
  - RSSA: Correspondence, 1997 (Box 25, Folder 28)
  - RSSA: Correspondence, 2000 (Box 25, Folder 29)
  - RSSA: Correspondence, 2001; 2002 (Box 25, Folder 30)
  - RSSA: Correspondence, 2004 (Box 25, Folder 31)
  - RSSA: Correspondence, 2005 (Box 25, Folder 32)
  - RSSA: Council of Municipal Retiree Organizations of New York City (COMRO), 1995; 2006 (Box 25, Folder 33)
  - RSSA: CSA Merger, 2004-2005 (Box 25, Folder 34)
  - RSSA: CSA Merger-Constitutional Considerations, Undated; 2002 (Box 25, Folder 35)
  - RSSA: Educational Cultural Program, 2005 (Box 25, Folder 36)
  - RSSA: Executive Board, 1998 (Box 25, Folder 37)
  - RSSA: Executive Board Minutes, 1991-1994 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - RSSA: Executive Board Minutes, 1995 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - RSSA: Executive Board Minutes, 1996 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - RSSA: Executive Board Minutes, 1997 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - RSSA: Executive Board Minutes, 1998-1999 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - RSSA: Executive Board Minutes, 2000 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - RSSA: Executive Board Minutes, 2001 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - RSSA: Executive Board Minutes, 2002 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - RSSA: Executive Board Minutes, 2003 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - RSSA: Executive Board Minutes, 2004 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - RSSA: Executive Board Minutes, 2005 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - RSSA: Executive Board Minutes, 2006 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - RSSA: Finances, 1995-1999; 2004 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - RSSA: Flyers, 2000 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - RSSA: History, 1996-2005 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - RSSA: Joint Association of Supervisors, 1997 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - RSSA: Labor Day Parade, 2006 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - RSSA: Leadership Conference (Queens), 1992 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - RSSA: Legislative Committee, 1997-2003 (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - RSSA: Levy, Jill, 2005-2006 (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - RSSA: Lobby Day-Member's Packet, 1998 (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - RSSA: Lobbying, 1996-1997 (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - RSSA: Lobbying, 1998-1999 (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - RSSA: Lobbying, 2002-2004 (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - RSSA: Lobbying, Dolores Goidel, 1998; 2002 (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - RSSA: Mailing Lists, Undated; 1997 (Box 26, Folder 26)
  - RSSA: Membership Application, [2002] (Box 26, Folder 27)
  - RSSA: Membership Figures, 2006 (Box 26, Folder 28)
  - RSSA: Membership Meeting, 1971 (Box 26, Folder 29)
  - RSSA: Membership Meetings, 1995-1996; 2002-2006 (Box 26, Folder 30)
  - RSSA: Mental Retardation and Developmental Disabilities Advisory Council (OMRDD); New York State (Dolores Goidel), 1998-1999 (Box 26, Folder 31)
  - RSSA: New York State Federation of School Administrators (AFSA), 2002-2006 (Box 26, Folder 32)
  - RSSA: Outing at Kutcher's, 1995 (Box 26, Folder 33)
  - RSSA: Position Papers, 1998-2004 (Box 26, Folder 34)
  - RSSA: Publicity, Undated; 1998-2002 (Box 26, Folder 35)
  - RSSA: Public Relations Committee, 1999 (Box 26, Folder 36)
  - RSSA: Reports, 2005 (Box 26, Folder 37)
  - RSSA: RSSA Bulletin, 1990-1995 (Box 26, Folder 38)
  - RSSA: RSSA News and Newsletters, 1972; 1996-2002 (Box 26, Folder 39)
  - RSSA: RSSA Times, 1983-1990 (Box 26, Folder 40)
  - RSSA: Retiree Volunteers, 1992 (Box 26, Folder 41)
  - RSSA: Retired Supervisors Group (RSSA predecessor), 1972-1977 (Box 26, Folder 42)
  - RSSA: Rizzuto, August, Retirement, 1995 (Box 26, Folder 43)
  - RSSA: Shanes, Irwin, 2006 (Box 26, Folder 44)
  - RSSA: Social Security, Undated; 2005 (Box 26, Folder 45)
  - RSSA: Souvenir Pen Certificate from Mayor Edward Koch, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 46)
  - RSSA: Spring Luncheons, 1988-1999 (Box 26, Folder 47)
  - RSSA: Tenure Plan, 1999 (Box 26, Folder 48)
  - RSSA: Twenty-Fifth Anniversary Luncheon, 1999 (Box 26, Folder 49)
  - RSSA: Welfare Fund, 1984; 1997-2000 (Box 26, Folder 50)
- Series V: Oversize Periodicals on Decentralization and Ocean Hill-Brownsville, 1968-1969
  Series V: Oversize Periodicals on Decentralization and Ocean Hill-Brownsville, 1968-1969. Included are issues of Urban Review, Center Forum and the New York Times Magazine.
  - Urban Review: Nov 1968; Jan 1969; Jun 1969; Sep 1969, 1968-1969 (Box 27)
  - Center Forum: Nov 13, 1968; May 15, 1969, 1968-1969 (Box 27)
  - New York Times Magazine: Feb 2, 1969 (Box 27)
- Series VI: Archived Websites, April 2014-ongoing; 3 websites in 3 archived websites.
  The Council of School Supervisors and Administrators is the collective bargaining unit for 6,100 Principals, Assistant Principals, Supervisors and Education Administrators who work in the NYC public schools and 200 Directors and Assistant Directors who work in city- subsidized Centers for Early Childhood Education. CSA The website contains its newsletter, CSA News, information on workshops and training, political action campaigns, agreements and contracts, and additional photographs and videos. The series also includes the website for their welfare fund and their Executive Leadership Institutes Professional Development (ELIPD) program.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
  Accruals
  New site crawls are accrued semiannually.
  Appraisal
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of elipd.org, csawf.org, and csa-nyc.org in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.